mytechlogy.com 2019-11-17

# Privacy Policy - MyTechLogy

### **Overview**

MyTechLogy.Com (the "Website") is owned by Sciente International Pte Ltd (hereafter referred to as "Sciente International", "we" or "us"). Sciente International is committed to protecting the privacy of MyTechLogy.Com users. We want to provide a safe, secure user experience. To that end, we have always had a robust and effective data protection program in place which complies with existing law and abides by the data protection principles. We have also recognised and fulfilled our obligations in updating and expanding this program to meet the demands of the EU General Data Protection Regulation. The following statement explains Sciente International's commitment to managing your Personal Information and sets out how and when Personal Information is collected, held, used or disclosed. 

This Privacy Policy only applies to data gathered on the MyTechLogy.Com web site "Website", and does not apply to any other information or web site including, but not limited to, affiliated companies. In this Privacy Policy, "affiliated companies" shall mean entities that control, are controlled by or are under common control with Sciente International.

We revised this Privacy Policy notice to comply with the GDPR, ensuring that all individuals whose Personal Information we process have been informed of why we need it, how it is used, what their rights are, who the information is disclosed to and what safeguarding measures are in place to protect their information.

### **Information Checks**

We periodically carry out reviews of website-wide data to identify and assess what Personal Information we hold, where it comes from, how and why it is processed and if and to whom it is disclosed. 

### **Policies & Procedures**

  * Data Protection – MyTechLogy.com stores all Personal Information on secure servers on Amazon Web Services (a GDPR-compliant hosting provider) and protected by physical, electronic and procedural safeguards against unauthorized access, use, modification, or deletion.
  * Data Retention & Erasure – we have ensured that Personal Information is stored, archived and destroyed compliantly and ethically. We have dedicated erasure procedures in place to meet the new ‘Right to Erasure’ obligation. If you no longer want MyTechLogy.com to store and process your Personal Data, please send us an email request at enquiry@mytechlogy.com. 
  * Data Breaches – our breach procedures ensure that we have safeguards and measures in place to identify, assess, investigate and report any personal data breach at the earliest possible time. Our procedures are robust and have been disseminated to all employees, making them aware of the reporting lines and steps to follow.
  * International Data Transfers, Storage & Third-Party Disclosures – where MyTechLogy.com stores or transfers Personal Information outside the EU, we have safeguarding measures in place to secure, encrypt and maintain the integrity of the data. Your data is stored in databases that are secured and protected by GDPR-compliant mechanisms on a third party hosting provider, Amazon Web Services.
  * Obtaining Consent - we have revised our consent mechanisms for obtaining personal data, ensuring that individuals understand what they are providing, why and how we use it and giving clear ways to consent to us processing their information. We have strengthened our process for recording user consent, making sure that we can evidence an affirmative opt-in, along with time and date records; and an easy to see and access way to withdraw consent at any time.
  * Direct Marketing - we have revised the wording and processes for direct marketing, including a clear opt-out mechanism for marketing subscriptions; a clear notice and method for opting out and providing unsubscribe features on all subsequent marketing materials.
  * Coach Agreements – where we use third-party affiliate coaches to view your professional profile information and your career analytics in order to deliver their coaching services to you we have drafted agreements with them to ensure that they meet and understand their/our GDPR obligations. However we cannot control the actions and practices of these coaches and cannot guarantee GDPR compliance on their behalf. 

### **Third Party Web Sites**

The Website and MyTechlogy mobile app contain links to third party web sites over which we have no control. We are not and cannot be responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other web sites linked from our Website. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those other web sites so that you can understand how they collect, use and share your information. 

### **Notification of Purpose**

The information we gather on the Website may be shared with any of the affiliated companies and coaches on a worldwide basis in order to deliver the products and services we offer to employers such as career analytics, career coaching services, and searches for job seekers or in order to undertake analysis of our database such as aggregate profiling of our registered users. 

We gather information about our Website users collectively, such as what areas users visit most frequently and what services users access the most. We only use such data anonymously and in the aggregate. Some of this data is analysed using, e.g., Google Analytics, a service offered by Google Inc. This information helps us determine what is most beneficial for our users, and how we can continually create a better overall experience for you. We may, in the future, share this information with our affiliated companies, but only in the aggregate, without identifying you individually, so that they too may understand how MyTechLogy.Com visitors use our Website, and also to create a better overall experience for you. 

We do not disclose your Personal Information to non-affiliated third parties, except to the extent necessary or appropriate to comply with applicable laws, rules or regulations or as required in legal proceedings. 

### **Types Of Personal Information Collected**

MyTechLogy.Com is an intelligent career development platform. We collect, use and retain the professional profile and contact information supplied by you via the site screens and mobile app Personal Information to facilitate the delivery of personalized career analytics and coaching services, job searches and applications through our Job-search Portal, professional training and skills upgrading through our Online IT Courses, and to facilitate your use of our Forum, as well as facilitating the provision or purchase of other services or products by us. 

For example, when you sign up to use a service, enter into a contest, or purchase a product, we may collect and retain Personal Information about you such as your name, IP address, country of residence, email address, qualifications or career history. We give you the option of uploading a display image or photo for your online profile. We may also collect and retain sensitive information about you such as information about your membership in a professional or trade association or trade union. At MyTechLogy.com we do not capture, and we ask that you not send or disclose either to us or to our coaches any other sensitive Personal Information. Examples of sensitive information include financial data, or data about your personal beliefs, race, ethnicity, etc. We may also ask you for other information, such as information on your interests, your likes and dislikes regarding the Website, the types of jobs you are interested in, etc., in an effort to deliver to you the best possible Website experience. If you consent to our collection and use of your Personal Information, we will communicate with you regularly with tips, advice and survey information on using the MyTechLogy.Com Website to maximise your career development. MyTechLogy.Com also provides registered users with the opportunity to opt-in or opt-out of these types of communications through a user profile page. If you choose to receive these types of communications at the time of registration, but later decide you no longer want to receive them, simply log in to your MyTechLogy.Com account and edit the opt-out settings in your profile. 

In addition, we may indirectly collect information about you when you use certain third party services available on the Website. For example, if you register on MyTechLogy.Com by using your LinkedIn user name and password, you authorise us to have access to and store the information from LinkedIn in your account profile. Such information will be subject to, and treated in accordance with, the policies and practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

You are not required to provide us with Personal Information. However, without sufficient Personal Information, MyTechLogy.Com may be limited in its ability to provide you with relevant content or services. 

Additionally, third party advertisers may collect information about your use of the site, such as the links you click on, number of visits, geographical location and online behaviour. You understand and agree that we exercise no control over such third party advertisers and their collection, use or disclosure of your Personal Information. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of these third party advertisers so you can understand how they collect, use and share your information. 

### **Use Of Personal Information**

We use the information we gather on the Website to identify you when you access the Website, respond to queries or requests submitted by you, process requests or applications submitted by you, or to fulfil any other reasonable purpose which may, in our ultimate discretion, be necessary. We also use the information for the purposes of operating and improving the Website, fostering a positive user experience, and delivering the products and services that we offer. 

If you have provided consent for us to do so, we may use the information we gather to inform you of other products or services available from us or our affiliated companies or to contact you about your opinion of current products and services, or about potential new products and services that may be offered. 

We may also use your contact information in order to send you e-mail or other communications regarding updates at the Website, or to contact you about your opinion of current products and services or potential new products and services that may be offered. We may also provide additional communications, promotions and information on new opportunities and additional job postings which may be of interest to you. The nature and frequency of these messages will vary depending upon the information we have about you. 

### **Disclosure of Personal Information**

We may disclose your resume to third party employers who have posted job opportunities that may be of interest to you on the Website when you use the Website to submit your resume for those jobs. When you submit your resume in response to a job posting, a copy of the resume is provided to the third party employer that posted the job opportunity. You are aware and understand that we do not, and are unable to, exercise control over the manner in which third party employers utilize your Personal Information. You are deemed to have consented to our disclosure of your resume to relevant third party employers by using the Website to submit your resume. 

In addition to the above, if you voluntarily provide Personal Information to us or to third parties by way of the Website, you understand and agree that you are deemed to have consented to our collection, use or disclosure of your Personal Information as necessary to carry out the purposes for which you provided the information. For example, if you disclose Personal Information in the "Reviews/Blogs" section of the Website and encourage other users to contact you for further information regarding your review, you are deemed to have consented to the Website publishing your post, containing the voluntarily-provided Personal Information, in order to carry out your intended communication. By voluntarily posting Personal Information on the Website, you also understand and agree that you are deemed to consent to other users sharing your post with third parties, whether by using the "Share" functionality provided by the Website, or by using direct links to pages on the Website, or in any other manner. 

We may disclose information to relevant third parties if you have consented to such disclosure. For example, if you indicate that you would like to receive information about the opportunities, products or services of third parties at the time you register for a MyTechLogy.Com account, we will supply your contact information to third parties such as employers, recruiters, data aggregators, marketers or others for the purpose of sending you e-mail or otherwise communicating with you. We may use data we have about you (such as the interests and preferences you have expressed) to determine whether you might be interested in the opportunities, products or services of a particular third-party. 

We disclose information to companies and individuals that we may hire to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include hosting web servers and data on Amazon Web Services, web traffic analytics and digital marketing services from Google Inc., and payment processing from Paypal Inc. We may, in the future, also use third party services for providing marketing assistance or customer service. These companies and individuals may have access to your Personal Information as may be necessary to perform their functions, and we will, in good faith, engage with those that we believe will protect this information in compliance with GDPR. However we cannot control the actions of these parties and cannot guarantee compliance on their behalf. 

We will disclose information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect our rights or property or our affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public. 

We may disclose and transfer information to a third party in the process of acquiring all or a substantial portion of our business, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets. In addition, in the event we become the subject of a bankruptcy proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, we or our trustee in bankruptcy may sell, license or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the bankruptcy court. You will be notified of sale of all or a substantial portion of our business to a third party via e-mail or through a prominent notice posted on the Website. 

### **Resume**

We give you the option of putting your resume in our database. It is not searchable by any third parties, but at your own volition you may share it with a coach or you may submit it to a third party as part of a job application. MyTechLogy.Com is not responsible for the retention, use, or privacy of resumes by coaches and third parties receiving your job application, including the submitted resume. You may remove your resume from our database at any time via your profile page. 

### **Updating Account Information**

We wish to ensure your Personal Information is complete, accurate and up to date. MyTechLogy.Com allows you to change or correct your Personal Information at any time. To do so, simply log into your MyTechLogy.Com account and you will find options for editing the information you have submitted 

### **Access to Personal Information**

You can gain access to the Personal Information you have provided by visiting our Website. If you need assistance to log in you can contact us by emailing enquiry@MyTechLogy.com. If you have not accessed your resume for some time we may also contact you to check your information is still correct. 

A request for access to the Personal Information we hold about you, to correct or update your Personal Information, to withdraw your consent for our collection, use or disclosure of your Personal Information, or in relation to an inquiry about privacy or compliance with personal data protection regulations, should be sent to enquiry@MyTechLogy.com. You may also request for information about the ways in which personal data has been or may have been used by the organisation within the past 1 year from the date of your request. You may delete your resume from MyTechLogy.Com's online database and/or deactivate your account at any time. 

### **Withdrawal of Consent**

You may, at any time, revoke consent for us to collect, use or disclose your Personal Information. Withdrawal of consent may be facilitated by deactivating your Website account. By doing so, you will no longer be able to utilize the services provided by the Website as such services are by their nature dependent on the collection, use or disclosure of Personal Information. 

### **Retention of Personal Information**

A user's Personal Information in our possession, power or control shall be deleted one month from deactivation of the respective user's account. Please bear in mind that if you have submitted Personal Information to prospective third party employers through our Job-search Portal, you will need to approach the third party employers directly to delete your Personal Information. 

### **Online Security**

We take all reasonable precautions to keep your personal data secure. Personal information used in online purchases from the Website is scrambled using Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") encryption technology before being sent over the Internet. When we receive your order, it is kept encrypted until we are ready to process it. SSL makes it difficult for your information to be stolen or intercepted while being transferred. Although we remain committed to keeping your personal data secure, you understand and agree that we cannot guarantee the successful encryption or the privacy of your personal details and credit card information. 

### **MyTechLogy.Com Database**

The information you provide is stored on the MyTechLogy.Com database. When providing information you agree this may be stored in our databases, which may be located internationally. To ensure the safety of your personal data, our web hosts encrypt information during transmission using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software. 

### **Cookies**

To enhance your experience at MyTechLogy.Com, we use a feature on your Internet browser called a "cookie". Cookies are small files that your Web browser places on your computer's hard drive. We use cookies for remembering user names and passwords and preferences, tracking click streams, and for load balancing. Because of our use of cookies, we can deliver faster service, consistent, updated results, and a more personalised Website experience. You have the option of setting your browser to reject cookies. However, doing this will hinder performance and negatively impact your experience on our Website. 

### **Feedback**

MyTechLogy.Com may provide an area on the Website where you can submit feedback. Any feedback that is submitted through this area becomes the property of MyTechLogy.Com. We may use this feedback at any time for any purposes, such as success stories for marketing purposes, or to contact you for further feedback on the Website. By submitting feedback, you are deemed to have consented to our use and/or disclosure of your feedback for the improvement and/or promotion of the Website. 

### **Privacy Policy Changes**

We may make changes to our privacy policy from time to time. We will post material changes on our Website so that you will always know what information we gather, how we intend to use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. Changes to the Privacy Policy are effective immediately, and incorporated into the Privacy Policy. Your use of the Website after such changes have been posted will constitute your agreement to the modified Privacy Policy and all of the changes. 

### **GDPR and Employees**

MyTechLogy.com understands that continuous employee awareness and understanding is vital to the continued compliance of the GDPR and have involved our employees in our implementation planning. Employee training on our data privacy policy is provided to all employees and forms part of our induction and periodic training programs. 

Thank you for using MyTechLogy.Com. We are committed to providing you with the best tools and advice to help you get ahead in your career. We welcome your feedback, questions and suggestions. Please contact us by email at [enquiry@MyTechLogy.com](mailto:enquiry@MyTechLogy.com), or by postal mail at: 

The CEO  
Sciente International Pte Ltd,  
51 Changi Business Park Central 2,  
#09-06 The Signature,  
Singapore 486066
